# Abdullah Al Masud

# Mobile App Developer (Android & Flutter)



- ♥ Flat-2B, House-59/60, Road-8, Block-C, Section-6, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216.
- almasud.arm@gmail.com
- **\**01737606053
- **?** GitHub □

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with experience in the mobile application development industry, specializing in creating native Android and Flutter-based mobile applications. Extensive background in these areas enables the production of high-quality, efficient mobile solutions to meet specific client needs.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering**

Dhaka International University ☑ 2015 – 2019 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### SKILLS

### Language

Java, Kotlin, XML, Dart, Python, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3, Basic Swift.

#### Library

Jetpack compose, Hilt, Bloc, GetIt, RxJava, Retrofit, Google Map etc.

#### **Development Tools**

Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, XCode, Git, Postman, Jira.

#### **Database**

MySQL, SQLite, Firebase Realtime & Firestore.

#### **Operating Systems**

MacOS, MS Windows, Android, Linux (Ubuntu)

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

NybSys Inc.

#### **Software Engineer (Android & Flutter)**

09/2021 - present | Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Android application development
- Flutter application development

XOR Geek

#### Mobile Application Engineer (Android & Flutter)

09/2020 - 09/2021 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Android application development
- Flutter application development
- Web application development

# PROJECTS

- Sentra PTT : A voice and data communication platform designed to enhance team collaboration through AI and edge computing. Its rich media features, photos, location sharing, calls & messaging provide this app the greatest power.

  Build tools: Android, Java, Protocol Buffers, Retrofit, RoomDB etc.
- **DrinkWell** ☑: A platform dedicated to providing clean and safe drinking water. Two Flutter-based mobile applications: **Pump Operator App** Enables operators to manage water ATM cards by registering users, recharging their cards, and generating daily reports.

**Dealer App** – Fund transfers from dealers to pump operators, track transactions etc.

Build with: Flutter, RestAPI, NFC tag reader etc.

• **Hokkaido Classic Golf Club App** □: A mobile app for Android platform that dedicated for a Golf Club. a registered member of the club can access and use the app.

Build tools: Android, Java, Retrofit etc.

- One-Click Order App □: A mobile app for Android/iOS platform where a registered member by the company can access the app and can order products by using the app. Build tools: Flutter
- One-Click Order App API & Admin Panel □: A web app that provides the API for the mobile.

  Build tools: Laravel, Bootstrap etc.
- **Xtreme VPN** <sup>□</sup>: A mobile app for Android platform where you experience unparalleled online security and freedom with Xtreme VPN, Xtreme VPN stands as a fortress to safeguard your digital presence.

Build tools: Android, Java, Kotlin, RestAPI etc.

• **Augmented Learn** : An educational app for Android platform that helps to teach preschool children with Augmented Reality. **Build tools: Android, Java, ARCore,** Adobe **photoshop, Blender** etc.